Guide to the Student Loan Office, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Student Loan Office, Yale University, records
1970-1983
RU 500
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
59.5
(52 boxes)
The records consist of correspondence, memoranda, ledgers and subject files documenting the operations and activities of the Yale Student Loan Office.
Yale University. Student Loan Office
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 11-A (YRG 11-A), Records of offices responsible for Yale undergraduate admissions and financial aid programs.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the records is partially restricted. See Collection Contents for details.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of correspondence, memoranda, ledgers and subject files documenting the operations and activities of the Yale Student Loan Office.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Student financial aid administration; Universities and colleges -- Administration; Yale University -- Administration; Yale University -- Students; Yale University. Student Loan Office
- Correspondence, disclosure and historical administrative records, circa 1970-1979; Accession 1981-A-032
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted until January 1, 2054.
  - Historical-Administrative Files (Box 1)
  - Historical-Administrative Files (Box 2)
  - Historical-Administrative Files (Box 3)
  - Historical-Administrative Files (Box 4)
  - Historical-Administrative Files (Box 5)
  - Historical-Administrative Files (Box 6)
  - Historical-Administrative Files (Box 7)
  - Historical-Administrative Files (Box 8)
  - Historical-Administrative Files (Box 9)
  - Vouchers (Box 10)
  - Historical-Administrative Files (Box 11)
  - Disclosure Piles (Box 12)
  - Disclosure Piles (Box 13)
  - Historical-Administrative Files (Box 14)
  - TPO brochures and information pamphlets (Box 15)
  - Disclosure Files (Box 16)
  - Disclosure Files (Box 17)
  - Correspondence Files (Box 18)
  - Administrative Correspondence (Box 19)
  - Correspondence Files (Box 20)
  - TPO/CRO Analysis Files Correspondence File, 1971-1972 (Box 21)
  - Correspondence File, 1972-1973; 1975-1976 (Box 22)
  - Correspondence Files (cont'd), 1975-1976 (Box 23)
  - Buyout Books (Box 24)
  - Buyout Books (Box 25)
  - Buyout Books (Box 26)
  - Buyout Books (Box 27)
  - Buyout Books (Box 28)
  - Buyout Books (Box 29)
  - Buyout Books (Box 30)
  - Buyout Books (Box 31)
  - Buyout Books (Box 32)
  - Buyout Books (Box 33)
  - Buyout Books (Box 34)
  - Buyout Books (Box 35)
  - Buyout Books (Box 36)
  - Accounting Ledgers (Box 37)
  - Accounting Ledgers (Box 38)
  - Accounting Ledgers (Box 39)
  - Accounting Ledgers (Box 40)
  - Buyout Files (Box 41)
  - Buyout Files (Box 42)
  - Buyout Files (Box 43)
  - Buyout Files (Box 44)
  - Buyout Files (Box 45)
  - Buyout Files (Box 46)
  - Buyout Files (Box 47)
  - Buyout Files (Box 48)
- Records, 1976-1983; Accession 1983-A-042
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2019.
  - GSL 7% and GSL 9% loans active files, 1976-1983
    - A - Bessent (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Bessette - C (Box 1, Folder 2 - 3)
    - D - Greet (Box 1, Folder 4 - 6)
    - Greggs - J (Box 1, Folder 7 - 10)
    - K - Mason (Box 1, Folder 11 - 15)
    - Massaro - Price, N. (Box 1, Folder 16 - 21)
    - Price, R. - Spradley (Box 1, Folder 22 - 28)
    - Stach - Z (Box 1, Folder 29 - 36)
    - GSL 7% and 9% corrections A - Z (Box 1, Folder 37 - 44)
    - FISL 7% Active file A - Z (Box 1, Folder 45 - 52)
- Records, 1983; Accession 1984-A-026
  - New Loan Notes
  - 9% GSL Spring Sale
    - Adler - Moriah, 1983 (Box 1, Reel 1)
    - Moulthrop - Zeno, 1983 (Box 1, Reel 2)
  - Update: 7% GSL Spring Sale
    - Acuna - Cornefl, 1983 (Box 1, Reel 2)
    - Crockell - MacIntosh, 1983 (Box 1, Reel 3)
    - MacLeod - Werthmimer, 1983 (Box 1, Reel 4)
    - White - Zapata, 1983 (Box 1, Reel 5)
  - Update: Additional GSL 7% and 9%
    - FISL 7% new, 1983 (Box 1, Reel 5)
    - FISL 7% serial, 1983 (Box 1, Reel 5)
    - Adkinson - Lentz, 1983 (Box 1, Reel 5)
    - Lewis - Zertinger, 1983 (Box 1, Reel 6)
    - FISL probable additions, 1983 (Box 1, Reel 6)
- Records, 1977-1979; Accession 1984-A-027
  The materials are open for research.
  - Tuition Postponement Plan - memos, proposals, and correspondence, 1977-1979 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Interest and Insurance Receivable, 1978 July-1979 June (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Atlas System - memos, proposals, and correspondence, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Records concerning the Tuition Postponement Option, 1970-1982; Accession 1992-A-074
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2018.
  - Economic Data - Tuition Postponement, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Tuition Postponement Option, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Optional Deferred Tuition Plan, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Nursing Brochure, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - TPO Seminar, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - TPO - Economics, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - TPO - Income Study, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Income Data, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - TPO Seminar - Proceedings, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - ODT - Plan Formulation (CRL,YEIP) TPO, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Assessments of the TPO Plan, 1973, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Seminar Vu-Graphs, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - TPO Information, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - C. Shaw - TPO File of Tapes and Record Formats, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Yale Educational Investment Plan, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - C. Shaw Data, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Special Conditions - Student Loan System, undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Student Loan User Manual, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - SLA Tapes, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Income Projections, undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - File Descriptions, undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Student Loan Master File Format and Specification, undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Student Loan Office Computer Work, undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Yale Computer Center Newsletter, undated (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Current and Historical Coding, undated (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence, Memos, Notes, 1980-1982 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Paying for a Yale Education II - Update and Options, undated (Box 1, Folder 29)